Contact

918-805-1300 (Mobile) wdmassey1@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/william-d-massey-bsn-rn-cnor-ccrn-csc-5b139b141 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Cardiovascular Disease Leadership Critical Care

Certifications

BLS

ACLS

CSC

CCRN

Certified Nurse Operative Room (CNOR)

Honors-Awards

"Healthcare Hero Award"

Outstanding Professional Service Award

Academic Achievement Award

Outstanding Student Leadership Award

Excellence Award in EBP

William D. Massey BSN, RN, CNOR, CCRN-CSC

Leader, Change Agent, Investor, Clinician, Consultant, and Entrepreneur

Houston, Texas

Summary

I am a baccalaureate-prepared Registered Nurse with over seven years of experience. I am specialty certified in critical care nursing, cardiac surgical nursing, and peri-operative nursing. I have received recognition from patients, co-workers, and hospital administration for providing outstanding nursing care through the course of my career. I have received superior performance evaluations in the top 20% of employees within a health system (including my most recent, in 2019), hospital-wide patient-nominated awards for nursing care, and recognition for speciality and sub-specialty national certifications. I graduated from the University of Oklahoma Health Sciences Center in 2012 with academic distinction and honors.

I recently accepted a nomination by my colleagues as the CVOR "Magnet Champion", and as such will serve on Houston Methodist's house-wide magnet designation committee as a representative and liaison for cardiovascular peri-operative services. In addition, I am an active member of Houston Methodist Hospital's Quality Improvement and Outcomes committee, a co-chair of CVOR's unit-based shared governance quality committee, a preceptor, skills validator, leader, and preceptor.

My areas of clinical expertise include critical care, hemodynamic monitoring, cardiovascular surgery from pre-operative assessment through the recovery period, vascular surgery, thoracic surgery, mechanical circulatory support (LVAD, IABP, Impella, etc.), heart failure, transplantation, and advanced life support. I feel most satisfied and motivated by serving as a leader and resource to my inter- and intra-disciplinary colleagues, encouraging unity and respect among staff, and empowering young clinicians to excel in their roles. During the 2020 COVID-19 crisis, I have been functioning

as an interim critical care educator for Houston Methodist's Center for Nursing Research, Education, and Practice.

My immediate interests and passions include business and finance, nursing and healthcare leadership, entrepreneurship, economics, investing, mentorship, and real estate. I am an avid reader; the majority of my free time is spent learning new and challenging skills outside of nursing, including computer programming, web design, physics, economics, and investment strategies. I also work one-on-one with clients as a personal finance and investing consultant. I am inspired by challenge and the opportunity to make a positive lasting impression in the lives of others.

Experience

Houston Methodist
RN III - CVOR
June 2018 - Present (2 years)
TMC

Massey Investment Holdings, LLC
President
February 2018 - Present (2 years 4 months)
Houston, Texas

Founding member and president of Massey Investment Holdings, LLC. Business focus presently centered around blockchain investing and cryptocurrency mining, IT solutions, financial advising, e-commerce, and equity markets. As President and the sole proprietor of Massey Investment Holdings, I maintain and oversee all aspects of operation, from accounting and bookkeeping, to hardware and software maintenance, to business development and financing. As my operation grows, I am seeking to expand into other industries and opportunities, including real estate, business acquisitions, and partnerships.

Owner of a financial blog focused on investing, personal finance, debt, and building and managing wealth.

Memorial Hermann Health System VAD Coordinator May 2017 - June 2018 (1 year 2 months) Houston, Texas Area

The VAD coordinator is a designated member of the heart transplant and VAD team(s) and is primarily responsible for coordinating clinical aspects of care from the evaluation phase for bridge to transplant or destination therapy, through post procedure, including patient assessment, education, treatment and management. The incumbent solves complex clinical problems and communicates with attending surgeons, cardiologists, fellows and residents. He/She develops, implements and monitors the mechanical assist policies and processes to improve patient care and coordinates and collaborates with heart transplant coordinators if or when patient becomes transplant candidate.

Provides coordination of care for patients requiring implantation of cardiac assist device including patients awaiting heart transplant or those having a device implanted as a permanent treatment; ensures that all pre-surgical radiological, diagnostics and consults are completed prior to surgical procedure.

Serves as primary liaison for cardiothoracic surgeon, cardiologists, other involved physicians and referring physicians during the evaluation, implantation and post surgical stages.

Attends daily rounds and discharge planning and provides necessary documentation in hospital EMR.

Serves as content expert for internal and external customers in the care of VAD patients; provides and collaborates on training for hospital nursing staff, EC, OR and community agencies (such as EMS) as needed for provision of care for the post operative VAD patient.

Provides education to patient and family during pre, intra-operative, post operative and discharge phases; plans and prepares patient and family for discharge to home, stabilization at home, and long-term care plan with outpatient clinic.

Collaborates with unit educators for device specific nurse competencies for ICU/floor nurse utilization.

More details available on request

St. John Medical Center Registered Nurse - ICU Float 2017 - 2017 (less than a year)

Tulsa, Oklahoma Area

Assessed, planned, implemented, and evaluated nursing care, utilizing the nursing process, to care for a wide array of critically ill patient with excellence and compassion in accordance with hospital standards and unit policies/

procedures. Cared for patients in the cardiovascular, neurosurgical, and medical intensive care settings.

Hillcrest Healthcare System Registered Nurse IV - ICU 2015 - 2017 (2 years)

Tulsa, Oklahoma Area

Assessed, planned, implemented, and evaluated nursing care, utilizing the nursing process, to care for a wide array of critically ill patient with excellence and compassion in accordance with hospital standards and unit policies/ procedures. Routinely provided care to Oklahoma Heart Institute's immediate post-operative cardiac surgery patients and coronary intervention patients. Collaborated with physicians and ancillary staff to provide care to patients requiring advanced supportive therapies including intra-aortic balloon pump, continuous renal replacement therapy, induced hypothermia, RotoProne therapy, and ventilator support. Participated in interdisciplinary teams to develop patient care plans on a daily basis. Responsible for training and orienting nurses to general intensive care unit nursing, open heart recovery, and continuous renal replacement therapy. Utilized the nursing process, critical thinking skills, and clinical knowledge to direct patient care and suggest treatment options to hospitalists, intensivists, and specialist physicians. Officially recognized by several patients for providing exceptional nursing care and subsequently recognized by the hospital CEO and CNO as a "Healthcare Hero" in 2016.

Shadow Mountain Behavioral Registered Nurse 2014 - 2015 (1 year)

Tulsa, Oklahoma Area

Assessed, planned, implemented, and evaluated nursing care, utilizing the nursing process, to care for adolescent individuals with varying psychiatric diagnoses with excellence and compassion in accordance with hospital standards and unit policies/procedures. Facilitated care for adolescents in need of psychiatric and behavioral treatment. Participated in an interdisciplinary care team to formulate treatment plans and establish goals for therapy.

St. Francis Hospital
Registered Nurse III - CVICU
2012 - 2014 (2 years)
Tulsa, Oklahoma Area

Assessed, planned, implemented, and evaluated nursing care, utilizing the nursing process, to care for critically ill patients with excellence and compassion in accordance with hospital standards and unit policies/ procedures. Consistently sought opportunities for self-improvement and professional development, and enthusiastically pursued advancement through the unit's acuity-based staffing ladder. Participated in the hospital's clinical ladder program, achieving the designation of Clinical Nurse III in 2013. Routinely cared for cardiothoracic surgery patients during the immediate post-operative period. Provided care to patients following complex vascular surgeries, TAVR procedures, and complex coronary interventions. Responsible for assessing, maintaining, and utilizing advanced supportive therapies such as the TandemHeart percutaneous ventricular assist device, intra-aortic balloon pump, continuous renal replacement therapy, and induced hypothermia. Selected on several occasions to function as the "Unit Leader" for the purpose of assisting the charge nurse with specified tasks and to serve as a resource for the nursing staff.

Education

University of Oklahoma Health Sciences Center Bachelor's degree, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (2008 - 2012)